<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dog on Jim Kalafut</title>
    <link>http://kalafut.net/tags/dog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dog on Jim Kalafut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://kalafut.net/tags/dog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Missing &#39;Mad Men&#39;</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-05-19-madmen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-05-19-madmen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So Mad Men is done. I&amp;rsquo;m glad. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think the show was nearly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/culture/cultural-comment/the-original-resonant-existentially-brilliant-mad-men-finale&#34;&gt;as good as others did&lt;/a&gt;. I started
becoming increasingly bored around season 3 or 4. Now I don&amp;rsquo;t have to think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this really isn&amp;rsquo;t about Mad Men, but rather time and entertainment. I watch very little of anything. What I
do watch (usually a couple hours per week, tops), has for a long time been a mix of movies and TV series. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some really
excellent TV in the past few years (The Wire, The Shield, Breaking Bad, Black Mirror, Sherlock, The Fall). But I&amp;rsquo;ve also started to question the
ROI of TV, even for the good shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finish a show like &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Shield&#34;&gt;The Shield&lt;/a&gt; I think, &amp;ldquo;Wow, what a great show, that was really worth it.&amp;rdquo; And then I finish a movie like &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Separation&#34;&gt;A Separation&lt;/a&gt; and think, &amp;ldquo;Wow, what a great show, that was really worth it&amp;rdquo;. In both cases I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied at the time. But then I start reviewing the time invested:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shield: 66 hours&lt;br /&gt;
A Separation: 2 hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have watched 33 movies in the time spent watching The Shield. So how do the experiences compare over that time? I think I overly inflate the quality of TV episodes in retrospect. If the show was good, the whole lot gets a good grade. But if I think back to stupid subplots that went nowhere and irritating characters that hung around for a season, then I start to recall the tiresome stretches. There are plenty of boring movies too, no matter how hard I tried to mine ratings
and recommendations to avoid them. But some key difference exist that suggest movies are a better choice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A movie offers a relatively new experience, as compared to the next episode in a TV series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Movies are usually structured to resolve, not leave one salivating for the next episode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no series investment (i.e. my yawning through three seasons of Mad Men because I&amp;rsquo;d already watched the previous four).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, movies also require a longer continuous chunk of time. They also require more mental energy to lock on to the new characters and plot. When I&amp;rsquo;m exhausted and just want some relaxation or distraction, a TV show is often desireable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy Mad Men is done, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy when House of Cards is done too. At that point I&amp;rsquo;ll be TV debt free. I&amp;rsquo;ve already started watching more movies, though it seems like TV series are nearly unavoidable when choosing what&amp;rsquo;s next to watch. I&amp;rsquo;ve not written off TV, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to very cautious before signing up for more long-running shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ah&amp;hellip; blog post is done. What to do now? Hmmm, &amp;ldquo;The Blacklist&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that&amp;rsquo;s pretty good&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>