<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jim Kalafut</title>
    <link>http://kalafut.net/categories/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jim Kalafut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://kalafut.net/categories/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another Todo List</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-17-yatl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-17-yatl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking quite a bit about writing a todo application. Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve used tons of them (who hasn&amp;rsquo;t), and I&amp;rsquo;ve formed my opinions about features, behaviors, appearances and architectures for this class of application. Now I want to roll my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is supposed to be a fun project that will hopefully be a useful project. Because it&amp;rsquo;s by me, for me, and controlled by me, I have thought about how much time will be spent tweaking the system instead of letting the system help me get stuff done. I&amp;rsquo;m not worried about that though, because I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; going to tweaking whatever system I&amp;rsquo;m using at the time&amp;ndash;no question. My hope is that my time is better spent improving a &lt;em&gt;product&lt;/em&gt; of my own, rather that using that time evaluating others&amp;rsquo; work and coming up with schemes to plug things together, move data to and fro, and otherwise smooth things out. It&amp;rsquo;s a chance to explore new technology, try out UI patterns for real (by using them daily), and hopefully build a thing that is, above all, something I&amp;rsquo;m happy with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>