<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jim Kalafut</title>
    <link>http://kalafut.net/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jim Kalafut</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://kalafut.net/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>In defense of DVDs</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-08-09-dvd-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-08-09-dvd-defense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve just re-enabled my Netflix DVD service for the umpteenth time. Streaming is usually
enabled (though it&amp;rsquo;s of dubious usefulness), and whether I&amp;rsquo;m getting DVDs is a matter of how
much time I&amp;rsquo;m spending on movies at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a general rule, DVDs are the only way for me to watch the movies I want. I use various movie
recommendation sources and my wishlist is filled with things that are not available on streaming
services, at least not Netflix nor Amazon. As for torrents&amp;hellip; They&amp;rsquo;re usually left for the odd case where
I can&amp;rsquo;t buy, rent or stream the movie anywhere. I have a job and I don&amp;rsquo;t mind paying for stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How bad is the streaming situation? I recently was searching Netflix for some of my top
recommendations from &lt;a href=&#34;http://criticker.com&#34;&gt;Criticker&lt;/a&gt; and went through nearly 20 movies before
coming across one that wasn&amp;rsquo;t DVD-only. Looking for a Bogart film to stream? Netflix has you
covered, with films involving Andrea, Dominic &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Keith Bogart!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this is not a big deal. DVDs are just fine. The iconic Netflix envelopes are occasionally
mocked as some vestige of a media age gone by, but I don&amp;rsquo;t buy into that. There is convenience
with streaming, but it&amp;rsquo;s marginal. I can wait a day for a movie, and if there are multiple DVDs
in the house then there will usually be no waiting ever. I&amp;rsquo;ll even say there is an advantage
to the DVD queue system: it reduces choice. Not of what to watch ever (something it increases
about 10x for Netflix), but for right &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;. My viewing time is limited, and I just as soon know
that movies A, B and C are options tonight and that&amp;rsquo;s it. Surfing around a list of mediocre choices
the Netflix thinks I might like in wholly unappealing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If streaming suddenly had the full library of movies, there would be no point for the DVDs. But
for now, in this weird state of media transition, I&amp;rsquo;m quite happy for the USPS to provide a steady
&lt;em&gt;DVD&lt;/em&gt; stream to my house, allowing me to watch almost anything I want.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Missing &#39;Mad Men&#39;</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-05-19-madmen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-05-19-madmen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So Mad Men is done. I&amp;rsquo;m glad. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think the show was nearly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/culture/cultural-comment/the-original-resonant-existentially-brilliant-mad-men-finale&#34;&gt;as good as others did&lt;/a&gt;. I started
becoming increasingly bored around season 3 or 4. Now I don&amp;rsquo;t have to think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this really isn&amp;rsquo;t about Mad Men, but rather time and entertainment. I watch very little of anything. What I
do watch (usually a couple hours per week, tops), has for a long time been a mix of movies and TV series. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some really
excellent TV in the past few years (The Wire, The Shield, Breaking Bad, Black Mirror, Sherlock, The Fall). But I&amp;rsquo;ve also started to question the
ROI of TV, even for the good shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I finish a show like &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Shield&#34;&gt;The Shield&lt;/a&gt; I think, &amp;ldquo;Wow, what a great show, that was really worth it.&amp;rdquo; And then I finish a movie like &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Separation&#34;&gt;A Separation&lt;/a&gt; and think, &amp;ldquo;Wow, what a great show, that was really worth it&amp;rdquo;. In both cases I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied at the time. But then I start reviewing the time invested:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Shield: 66 hours&lt;br /&gt;
A Separation: 2 hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have watched 33 movies in the time spent watching The Shield. So how do the experiences compare over that time? I think I overly inflate the quality of TV episodes in retrospect. If the show was good, the whole lot gets a good grade. But if I think back to stupid subplots that went nowhere and irritating characters that hung around for a season, then I start to recall the tiresome stretches. There are plenty of boring movies too, no matter how hard I tried to mine ratings
and recommendations to avoid them. But some key difference exist that suggest movies are a better choice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A movie offers a relatively new experience, as compared to the next episode in a TV series.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Movies are usually structured to resolve, not leave one salivating for the next episode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no series investment (i.e. my yawning through three seasons of Mad Men because I&amp;rsquo;d already watched the previous four).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, movies also require a longer continuous chunk of time. They also require more mental energy to lock on to the new characters and plot. When I&amp;rsquo;m exhausted and just want some relaxation or distraction, a TV show is often desireable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy Mad Men is done, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy when House of Cards is done too. At that point I&amp;rsquo;ll be TV debt free. I&amp;rsquo;ve already started watching more movies, though it seems like TV series are nearly unavoidable when choosing what&amp;rsquo;s next to watch. I&amp;rsquo;ve not written off TV, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to very cautious before signing up for more long-running shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ah&amp;hellip; blog post is done. What to do now? Hmmm, &amp;ldquo;The Blacklist&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that&amp;rsquo;s pretty good&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public speaking</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-02-23-public-speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-02-23-public-speaking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Useful, concise advice on public speaking, even for non-nerds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://dave.cheney.net/2015/02/17/practical-public-speaking-for-nerds&#34;&gt;Practical public speaking for Nerds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-02-19-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-02-19-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Federal Judge Paul Cassell, on administering a mandatory minimum sentence
to a 24 year old for three marijuana sales:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If he had been an aircraft hijacker, he would have gotten 24 years in prison.
If he’s been a terrorist, he would have gotten 20 years in prison. If he was a
child rapist, he would have gotten 11 years in prison. And now I’m supposed to
give him a 55-year sentence? I mean, that’s just not right.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://abcnews.go.com/US/federal-judge-regrets-55-year-marijuana-sentence/story?id=28869467&#34;&gt;Full story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train Big. Snow Fluffy.</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-02-07-train_snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-02-07-train_snow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m usually the last to see viral videos, and even later to pass them on, but this battle of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yja2VmZOfdA&#34;&gt;train vs. snow&lt;/a&gt;
must be shared. It&amp;rsquo;s so good, Peter Jackson &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e9K7fueW4Bk#t=140&#34;&gt;stole the idea&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; (2001).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It does prompt the question: why do locomotives need windows?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infant car seats</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-02-03-car-seats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-02-03-car-seats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake: installing an infant car seat can be strenuous work.
You need to achieve a fair amount of compression for the seat to stay put. This will
probably require sitting or standing on the seat while pulling hard on the
belt strap. If it seems easy, you&amp;rsquo;re probably not putting the seat in firmly enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides adjusting your expectation of work, here are a couple of tips I&amp;rsquo;ve
discovered over the years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re struggling to grip the belt, try wrapping it around a strong dowel, or
even a large screwdriver. This will provide you a handle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be efficient! If you are not pulling up directly in line with the natural path
of the belt from the buckle, you&amp;rsquo;re going to have to pull &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt; harder for
the same results. What I do whenever possible is pull the seat fabric out of the
way to provide a path up through a gap in the seat, instead of going around
the outside. The difference is dramatic. If there was one tip I wish I&amp;rsquo;d been told
years ago, it would be this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above applies to toddler seats too, but they&amp;rsquo;re much easier to get right in the
first place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have a Nexus 7? Get the Chrome Beta</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-02-01-chrome-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-02-01-chrome-beta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Chrome browser on Nexus 7 has never had the &lt;em&gt;Close All Tabs&lt;/em&gt; function like its brother on the phone. This made no sense, was annoying, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/chromium/issues/detail?id=268157&#34;&gt;dragged on forever&lt;/a&gt;. Fortunately, the end is near. You can now download Chrome version 40 via the Chrome Beta app on &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.chrome.beta&#34;&gt;Google Play&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Close All Tabs&lt;/em&gt; is accessed by long-pressing the usual tab close X.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A First Look At Fossil SCM</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-29-fossil-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-29-fossil-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of taking a hard look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fossil-scm.org/&#34;&gt;Fossil&lt;/a&gt; for source control. I&amp;rsquo;d heard
of it a long time ago, but only briefly considered it before getting swept up in the
rise of Mercurial and git. The only thing that put it back on the radar was a
brief mention in some Hacker News discussion, and a recent &lt;a href=&#34;http://twit.tv/show/floss-weekly/320&#34;&gt;FLOSS Weekly
episode&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used git daily at work and at home, and I know it well. I like it too, and it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly powerful.  The world has Github, which is both convenient super-productive,
so why spend time looking at Fossil? If it was just another DVCS with a different
different syntax, I&amp;rsquo;d probably not stay long. But it&amp;rsquo;s more that that, and the
differences from git are intriguing, so I&amp;rsquo;m trying it out in my workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some initial impressions (since this is the only time I&amp;rsquo;ll have them), in no
particular order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installation is simple on all platforms I&amp;rsquo;ve tried (OSX, Win7, Linux).  While I understand that &lt;code&gt;brew/aptitude install blah&lt;/code&gt; is easy too, it isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;simple&lt;/em&gt; when
that installation results in dozens of packages/files/folders being installed. Fossil is a small, standalone
binary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making new repos is easy just like git, but I like Fossil&amp;rsquo;s all-in-one-file approach better than the git&amp;rsquo;s pile of files under &lt;code&gt;/.git&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I like being able to check out of branch from the repo and just getting those files in whatever folder I&amp;rsquo;m in,
and opposed to cloning the repo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The basic CLI is fine, though I&amp;rsquo;m so used to git it will take time to really judge this one fairly. The breadth of commands and options in git dwarfs Fossil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The built-in server is great, and is the main thing that piqued my interest. The web UI gives a good overview of repo action, but also provides an integrated wiki and ticket system. All of this is versioned and part of the same repo file. At first blush it sounds like just bolting on features (there are dozens of wikis and tickets systems out there&amp;hellip;), but IMHO it&amp;rsquo;s really nice to get these basics for free, attached right to the project. Don&amp;rsquo;t use them if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to, but they&amp;rsquo;re there if needed.  (Oh, and that server process running on Windows: 1.5 MB of memory usage&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sync between repos has worked flawlessly. The model, for better and worse, is
basically that everything is connected and global. There aren&amp;rsquo;t a bunch of local
branches and forks and splinter repos.  I was able to set up Fossil on my VPS
in less than 10 minutes as a more central sync point, but syncing between
any two repos works equally well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are no submodules, which I&amp;rsquo;m not crying over.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I miss &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kernel.org/pub/software/scm/git/docs/git-rebase.html&#34;&gt;rebase&lt;/a&gt;. (&lt;strong&gt;Warning: start of rant&lt;/strong&gt;) There are some fairly dug-in anti-rebase philosophies held by the
Fossil principals that seem more stubborn &amp;amp; contrarian than useful. Their notion
that rebase is antithetical to an SCM&amp;rsquo;s core role indicates a lack of understanding
of rebase. Let&amp;rsquo;s just take the &amp;ldquo;preserve all history&amp;rdquo; ideal to an absurd extreme and
say it&amp;rsquo;s unacceptable that one can simply use their backspace key with no record of it. That&amp;rsquo;s my reaction when I read the old anti-rebase posts on the Fossil mailing list.
rebase is used to clean things up before publication.  Just like I&amp;rsquo;ll edit files before
committing them, so I&amp;rsquo;ll edit/rearrange commits before publishing them. That&amp;rsquo;s it.
Anyone whose had to collaborate on a Word document, let me ask you
this: how pleasant is it to have all edits by everyone visible? You&amp;rsquo;d probably just
like to read the document, at least in most cases. Well without easy squash and
rebase, it seems harder to get branches in a good state with Fossil. Deal breaker? No. But definitely a bit frustrating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I miss the git staging area and staging/reverting parts of edits. I do agree
the staging area can be confusing to newcomers, but it quickly becomes a
useful step in the workflow. There is probably just a different working in Fossil
that I need to learn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fossil documentation is a bit of a mixed bag, but is pretty good overall.
The system isn&amp;rsquo;t nearly as complicated as git and really doesn&amp;rsquo;t need a lot of
documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The community is inviting, and responsive. I submitted a
ticket for a very minor issue and it was fixed (on a development branch) in
less than four hours.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The whole thing is just a bit quirky, in a good way. The main author, D. Richard
Hipp (of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sqlite.org/&#34;&gt;SQLite&lt;/a&gt; fame), basically says that he wrote Fossil to manage SQLite and if others like it, fine. But then there are pockets of diehard Fossil zealots from
disparate backgrounds. The whole thing is less serious, less complicated, and
more fun than git.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time I&amp;rsquo;ll get into how I&amp;rsquo;m actually using Fossil for side projects differently
than what I could do with git.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS? You should probably try TTR</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-24-in-support-of-ttr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-24-in-support-of-ttr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a long-time consumer of RSS feeds, I was shocked along with many others at
the fairly sudden termination of Google Reader. Though there wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything
extraordinarily special about GR for me, it did offer a clean, simple way to browse
feeds and have the status sync across devices. Like everyone else, I set about
finding a replacement, and was pretty sure I&amp;rsquo;d find one in short order that met my
expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many were major departures from the clean, boring, email-like lists that I liked
and was looking for. A lot of the ones trying to mimic the old layout couldn&amp;rsquo;t deliver
on performance, or a mobile app, or were a bit spendy for my liking, etc. So for over a year I floated around, trying this and that, never feeling
at all settled. Then I saw reference in a Hacker News comment thread about
&lt;a href=&#34;http://tt-rss.org/&#34;&gt;Tiny Tiny RSS&lt;/a&gt; (TTR) and decided to give it a try.  Great decision,
and I&amp;rsquo;ve not once been left wanting for a better RSS reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main hurdle for most people is that you will have to host the thing yourself.
If you can stomach that, you&amp;rsquo;ll be extremely happy. Hell, your nerd circle can
easily mooch off of your server if they want, since it&amp;rsquo;s easy to create individual
accounts. What you&amp;rsquo;ll get in return for your efforts is a very good web and App
experience (at least on Android&amp;hellip; don&amp;rsquo;t know about iOS), delivering what you&amp;rsquo;d
expect from a basic RSS aggregator, on your terms and server. All nice and
GPL&amp;rsquo;d&amp;hellip; Your RSS Reader won&amp;rsquo;t be going out of business until you quit paying your server bills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for maintenance? Basically zero after you get it set up. So don&amp;rsquo;t worry about
that. It is well worth the effort to try out if you&amp;rsquo;re dissatisfied with your RSS situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/rss&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Jekyll?</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-22-why-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-22-why-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently asked why I switched from Octopress to Jekyll. I don&amp;rsquo;t have an interesting answer, because there weren&amp;rsquo;t any particularly strong reasons. The overarching goal was that of simplifying. For this blog, the idea of going with stock Jekyll hosted on Github pages is about the simplest way to write and publish a static blog. It certainly isn&amp;rsquo;t the &lt;em&gt;easiest&lt;/em&gt; way to have a blog, but for me, &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; includes the idea that the blog content and structure is stored simply and accessibly. There are a million hosted blog sites that could have me writing in seconds with zero administration, but then I&amp;rsquo;d be uncomfortably tied to their platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is probably simpler than Octopress, so I went with it. I&amp;rsquo;ve read &lt;a href=&#34;https://lauris.github.io/blogging/2014/08/16/jekyll-vs-octopress/&#34;&gt;stronger opinions&lt;/a&gt; on this matter,
but it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fair for me to make any claims because I&amp;rsquo;m a novice with
both platforms and my blog needs are minimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, I&amp;rsquo;m definitely happy with being able to write files on Github, press Commit, and have the task done. That is definitely a bit better than my previous workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;border: 2px none; border-radius:4px; padding: 0.35em; background: #60b044; color: white;&#34;&gt;Commit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And Suddenly My Best Phone Is Junk</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-20-lollipop-pos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-20-lollipop-pos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I bought the Nexus 4 shortly after it came out. I&amp;rsquo;d been living through a few
bad years of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://phandroid.com/2013/04/30/htc-thunderbolt-apology/&#34;&gt;HTC Thunderbolt&lt;/a&gt;, which was probably the worst
phone I&amp;rsquo;ve owned. Aside from being a bad phone, Verizon was &lt;em&gt;extremely&lt;/em&gt;
slow about updates for that device. I recall waiting over a year just for Android 4.0.
Making a break from Verizon to a Nexus device sounded great, and having
only consumed a few reviews of the Nexus 4, I made the leap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; been great, or at least very good. Yeah the camera is pretty much crap, and the lack of SD is annoying at times, but I don&amp;rsquo;t care. The phone is snappy, feels and looks good, and gets those
wonderful, wonderful software updates oh so quickly.  Combined with a sweet
$30/month unlimited data T-Mobile plan, it&amp;rsquo;s been a excellent setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About those wonderful Android updates&amp;hellip; Wonderful does not mean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone slows &lt;em&gt;waaaay&lt;/em&gt; down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone locks up randomly, multiple times daily, requiring hard reboots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bluetooth doesn&amp;rsquo;t work reliably&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marquee new &amp;ldquo;Smart Lock&amp;rdquo; feature only occasionally works&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone can&amp;rsquo;t do phone things, like make/receive calls. (Seems I&amp;rsquo;m
&lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/android/issues/detail?id=82949#c483&#34;&gt;not the only one&lt;/a&gt; experiencing this.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I could just reduce the battery life to about 4 hours I&amp;rsquo;d have me a Thunderbolt all over again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Android_Lollipop&#34;&gt;Android Lollipop&lt;/a&gt; is, in it current
state, a huge disappoint for me, and a growing source of frustration. I have fears
that Google may consider the Nexus 4 obsolete, as they do this &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.google.com/p/android/issues/detail?id=41626#c68&#34;&gt;Nexus 4 bug&lt;/a&gt;.  But it&amp;rsquo;s not obsolete
to me by a long shot. Overall it worked great, and should still be working great.
I don&amp;rsquo;t want to even contemplate a new phone, nor do I have the time, patience,
interest or energy to be reinstalling old images, non-stock ROMs, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So please, Google, fix your damn software already.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing slices to variadic functions</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-18-slice-to-variadic-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-18-slice-to-variadic-functions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I knew about variadic functions, and the &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; syntax, but I&amp;rsquo;d assumed that was
limited to the function declaration. When I tried to pass a slice of arguments
as the final parameter of a call to a variadic function, I got errors. The
answer is of course in the spec, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t find it quickly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;v := foo(bar, baz...)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; shows up again. Here&amp;rsquo;s the relevant section of the spec:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org/ref/spec#Passing_arguments_to_..._parameters&#34;&gt;Passing arguments to &amp;hellip; parameters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yet Another Todo List</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-17-yatl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-17-yatl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking quite a bit about writing a todo application. Over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve used tons of them (who hasn&amp;rsquo;t), and I&amp;rsquo;ve formed my opinions about features, behaviors, appearances and architectures for this class of application. Now I want to roll my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is supposed to be a fun project that will hopefully be a useful project. Because it&amp;rsquo;s by me, for me, and controlled by me, I have thought about how much time will be spent tweaking the system instead of letting the system help me get stuff done. I&amp;rsquo;m not worried about that though, because I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;strong&gt;always&lt;/strong&gt; going to tweaking whatever system I&amp;rsquo;m using at the time&amp;ndash;no question. My hope is that my time is better spent improving a &lt;em&gt;product&lt;/em&gt; of my own, rather that using that time evaluating others&amp;rsquo; work and coming up with schemes to plug things together, move data to and fro, and otherwise smooth things out. It&amp;rsquo;s a chance to explore new technology, try out UI patterns for real (by using them daily), and hopefully build a thing that is, above all, something I&amp;rsquo;m happy with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brokenmold: A New Hope</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-16-a-new-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-16-a-new-hope/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first post to this blog was a little over a year ago. I had hoped to post much more during the year, but that clearly didn&amp;rsquo;t happen. After reviewing things, I decided the only way to fix them was to change the blogging software. OK, not really. I&amp;rsquo;ll do no retrospective other than to say that post frequency was less than I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, I did change the blogging software! Here are a few reasons why the new setup should be &lt;em&gt;no worse&lt;/em&gt; than the previous one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hosting on Github instead of my own VPS is just a little bit easier (barely).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ability to create and edit files on Github is pretty nice, especially for this bloggy-type stuff. Fullscreen dark mode editing, combined with their Markdown previewer, is better than my Vim environment of 2014.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to do little in the way of customization of this thing, though I&amp;rsquo;ll probably nudge it off of the Jekyll defaults (like, maybe, changing the footer to say something other than &amp;ldquo;Write an awesome description for your new site…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Jekyll</title>
      <link>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-12-hello-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kalafut.net/post/2015-01-12-hello-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to move this thing to Github, so say hello to &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not going
to bother waiting for things to settle into their final form before pushing it, so
enjoy a bunch of boilerplate Jekyll look, free, and content for a bit. It will at
least provide a modicum of incentive to wrap up the migration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://brokenmold.net/blog/2014/10/09/hello-konigspress/&#34;&gt;Königspress&lt;/a&gt;, we hardly knew ya.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>